[
    {
        "question": "How many bits of zero does the following netmask have? 255.255.255.248",
        "answers": ["3", "4", "8", "2"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ARP protocol helps with:",
        "answers": [
            "Determining the MAC address when the IP address is known",
            "Determining the IP address when the MAC address is known",
            "Determining the IP address when the DNS server is known"
        ],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct host range for the subnet in which we can find the IP address 192.168.168.188/255.255.255.192 ?",
        "answers": [
            "192.168.168.128-192",
            "192.168.168.129-191",
            "192.168.168.128-190",
            "192.168.168.129-190"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the broadcast address for subnet 200.35.1.192/27?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "200.35.1.223"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following netmask: 255.255.0.0, the network part(network length) is formed by a number of bits equal to",
        "answers": ["8", "24", "16", "impossible to determine"],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In TCP, bytes not read from the stream:",
        "answers": [
            "A stream does not have bytes into his composition",
            "are lost - but their count is reported as an error to the user",
            "Are lost",
            "Stay available for the next read"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the values of the network address and the netmask in the default route?",
        "answers": [
            "0.0.0.0 255.255.255.0",
            "255.255.255.255 0.0.0.0",
            "127.0.0.1 255.255.255.0",
            "0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following address can be a valid host IP that can be allocated to a host:",
        "answers": [
            "193.231.21.0",
            "18.19.20.255",
            "223.245.256.17"
        ],
        "correct": "ab"
    },
    {
        "question": "Not all IP addresses from the class 192.168.0.0/8 are private",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "A TCP header is larger than a UDP header by how many bytes?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "12"
    },
    {
        "question": "The checksum in the IP header is computed:",
        "answers": [
            "when passing through each switch and hub in order to ensure consistency",
            "on each router",
            "on the source and destination hosts",
            "every time a router believes the packet has been altered"
        ],
        "correct": "bc"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid IP/Netmask combination?",
        "answers": [
            "209.220.186.8/255.255.255.248",
            "None of the combinations are correct",
            "209.220.186.8/255.255.255.240",
            "209.220.186.8/255.255.255.252",
            "209.220.186.8/255.255.255.240"
        ],
        "correct": "ad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following IP addresses cannot be broadcast addresses?",
        "answers": [
            "192.168.0.255",
            "200.0.0.33",
            "10.0.1.254",
            "25.0.2.31"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following addresses can be valid network addresses provided appropriate network masks?",
        "answers": [
            "193.231.20.2",
            "193.231.20.4",
            "193.231.20.1",
            "193.231.20.0",
            "193.231.20.3"
        ],
        "correct": "bd"
    },
    {
        "question": "A company has three departments: Offices, Public and Managers. The offices have 123 computers, Public Relationship has 29 computers and Managers have 5 computers. The company wants to make a network such that: - every computer has access to the internet - have minimum costs - it must be certainly known from which department some webpages are accessed from the HQ in another city Provide a good configuration for these requirements:",
        "answers": [
            "3 subnetworks, 192.168.0.0/24, 192.168.1.0/24, 192.168.2.0/24 for every department and connect every subnet directly to the internet, using NAT, through a different provider",
            "1 subnetwork for all the company, 192.168.0.0/24, connect computers to internet through a router which translates every address IP to a public IP address with different class depending on department",
            "3 subnetworks, 192.168.0.0/25, 192.168.0.128/27, 192.168.0.160/29, one router which translates the first network to 30.0.0.1, second to 30.0.0.2, and third to 30.0.0.3",
            "3 subnetworks, 192.168.0.0/25, 192.168.0.128/27, 192.168.0.160/29 and connect them to a central router which translates all the IPs on 192.168.0.0/24 with the IP 30.0.0.5"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are not contained in a routing table?",
        "answers": ["gateway", "the network interface", "the netmask", "source address"],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the broadcast address of the network 190.60.16.0/28?",
        "answers": [
            "190.60.16.31",
            "190.60.16.255",
            "190.60.16.15",
            "190.60.16.7"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens after receiving one duplicate Acknowledgment?",
        "answers": [
            "none of the answers are correct",
            "Congestion Window is set to 1 MSS",
            "Congestion Window is cut in half",
            "Congestion Window is cut in half and grows exponentially"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the last valid host on the network that 10.215.81.114 / 255.240.0.0 is a part of?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "10.223.255.254"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following network address: 192.0.2.64 . How many net masks can it be used with?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "accept() is required in any UDP server",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider one SWITCH and 10 PC's connected to it. Which of the following is false?",
        "answers": [
            "when PC1 sends a message to PC5, the message will be received and processed just by PC5 and the answer of PC5 will be received and processed just by PC1",
            "when PC1 sends a message to PC5, the message will be received by all the PC's, but only PC5 processes it; the answer is sent back and received only by PC1",
            "when PC1 sends a message to PC5, the message will be received by all the PC's, each of them sending back an answer",
            "when PC1 sends a message to PC5, the message will be received by all the PC's but only PC5 processes it; the answer will be also received by all the PC's but only PC1 will process it"
        ],
        "correct": "bcd"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the netmask of the minimum sized network that has as broadcast 70.71.79.255 and also contains the host IP address 70.71.79.240 ?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "255.255.255.224"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why would an ISP aggregate smaller networks into a larger one?",
        "answers": [
            "It does not ever aggregate networks.",
            "It can't store information about each network individually",
            "In order to reduce the number of entries in the routing table of the router connecting the ISP to the Internet",
            "In order to group all networks for a specific client together"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many bits of 0 are in the following netmask? 255.255.255.254?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the netmask of the largest network with the address 84.176.0.0 ? (as x.y.z.t)",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "255.240.0.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the Congestion Window is below the Threshold:",
        "answers": [
            "The window grows linearly",
            "The congestion window grows exponentially",
            "The window is set to 1 MSS"
        ],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the address 137.25.28.0/255.255.254.0 provide the maximum number of valid subnets that can be obtained from splitting this network",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "128"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following can be a mask, such that 62.244.89.16 is a valid network address?",
        "answers": ["255,255,255,252", "/29", "255,255,255,248", "/27", "255.255.255.128"],
        "correct": "abd"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a mask /29 mean?",
        "answers": [
            "Is equivalent to 255.255.255.248",
            "The maximum number of IP addresses that can be assigned to hosts is 29",
            "The maximum number of IP addresses that can be assigned to hosts is 6",
            "The maximum number of IP addresses that can be assigned to hosts is 8"
        ],
        "correct": "ac"
    },
    {
        "question": "What netmask is needed to split a network with address 133.25.0.0/16 in 1000 subnets of 14 hosts each?",
        "answers": ["/21", "/28", "/19", "/15"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a private IP address ?",
        "answers": ["192.168.24.43", "172.15.14.36", "168.172.19.40", "12.0.0.2"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are valid subnetwork addresses ?",
        "answers": [
            "177.91.107.0/30",
            "177.91.154.2/30",
            "177.91.107.144/29",
            "177.91.107.1/25"
        ],
        "correct": "cd"
    },
    {
        "question": "connect() is required in any TCP server",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "UDP is not located at the Link layer",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if the Gateway in a Routing table entry is 0.0.0.0?",
        "answers": [
            "The router drops the packet as there is no such gateway IP address",
            "This is not possible",
            "All packets will be directed to 0.0.0.0",
            "The router puts the packet on the associated network interface with this route"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IP field helps to check the order of the fragments?",
        "answers": ["identifier", "ttl", "flag", "offset"],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the closest number to the largest routing table in the case of class full IP Addressing?",
        "answers": ["2^16", "2^7+2^14+2^21", "2^32", "2^8+2^16"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A TCP connection is terminated through:",
        "answers": [
            "a  4-way handshake",
            "a 3-way handshake",
            "a 2-way handshake",
            "none of the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correct": "ab"
    },
    {
        "question": "254.255.0.0 is a valid netmask",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of the IP protocol?",
        "answers": [
            "Is considered an unreliable protocol",
            "It affects packet routing",
            "Is a connection-oriented protocol",
            "It defines the Internet addressing system"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Write as [network address]/[xx] - in the most compact and ordered way - the addressing space 62.255.254.224...63.64.0.31. (if multiple combinations are needed write them separated by comas without spaces or other characters)",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "62.255.254.224/27,62.255.255.0/24,63.0.0.0/10,63.64.0.0/27"
    },
    {
        "question": "The broadcast for 192.120.0.1/16 is 192.120.255.255",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the range of all IPs in which the following given IP resides :194.168.19.69/28 ?",
        "answers": [
            "194.167.19.68 – 194 .167.19.83",
            "194.168.19.64 – 194.168.19.87",
            "194.168.19.0 - 194.168.19.15",
            "194.168.19.64 – 194.168.19.79"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "The network address cannot be calculated using the netmask and an IP address",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following code is a: \n listen(s, 5); while (1) {\n memset(&client, 0, sizeof(client));\nl = sizeof(client);\n c = accept(s, (struct sockaddr *) &client, &l);\nif (fork() == 0) {\nworker(); }\nwait(0); }",
        "answers": ["iterative server", "concurrent server", "peer to peer server", "concurrent multiplexed server"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following IP sets belong to 209.220.186.12/255.255.255.252 ip class?",
        "answers": [
            "209.220.186.10, 209.220.186.11, 209.220.186.12, 209.220.186.13, 209.220.186.14, 209.220.186.15, 209.220.186.16, 209.220.186.17",
            "209.220.186.12, 209.220.186.13, 209.220.186.14, 209.220.186.15, 209.220.186.16, 209.220.186.17, 209.220.186.14, 209.220.186.18",
            "209.220.186.12, 209.220.186.13, 209.220.186.14, 209.220.186.15",
            "209.220.186.13, 209.220.186.14, 209.220.186.15, 209.220.186.16"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two connected routers are configured with RIP routing. What will be the result when a router received a routing update that contains a higher-cost path to a network already in its routing table?",
        "answers": [
            "the updated information will be added to the existing routing table",
            "the update will be ignored and no further action will occur",
            "the updated information will replace the existing routing table entry",
            "the existing routing table entry will be deleted from the routing table and all routers will exchange routing updates to reach convergence"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following addresses is a public IP address assignable to a computer ?",
        "answers": ["172.16.23.201", "1.0.0.1", "10.5.125.4", "225.46.130.1"],
        "correct": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many /27 networks are needed such that they can be supernetted to a /24 network?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "193.231.20.0/24 can be divided in exactly X subnets of equal sizes. X=?",
        "answers": ["7 subnets", "14 subnets", "5 subnets", "8 subnets", "4 subnets"],
        "correct": "de"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which host range is the IP address 175.156.68.80 255.255.255.192?",
        "answers": ["175.156.68.64-128", "175.156.68.64-126", "175.156.68.65-126", "175.156.68.65-128"],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "ARP can be used for...",
        "answers": [
            "Mapping public virtual addresses to private IP addresses",
            "publishing websites to the internet",
            "sending emails very fast",
            "Mapping network addresses to physical (MAC) addresses"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCP is located at the Transport layer",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Broadcasting is",
        "answers": [
            "When a transmitted packet is received and processed by every machine on the network",
            "When a transmitted packet is received by every machine on the network but processed by only one of them",
            "When a transmitted packet is received by every machine on the network but processed by none of them",
            "A mechanism which is used when the transmission of a packet fails"
        ],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "255.192.0.0 is a valid netmask for the network",
        "answers": ["132.128.0.0", "192.128.0.0", "None of the choices", "192.193.1.0"],
        "correct": "ab"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time-to-live for a packet(TTL) is expressed in:",
        "answers": [
            "seconds",
            "the number of routers the packet has already passed through( incremented by 1)",
            "routers/second",
            "the number of routers the packet is allowed to pass",
            "milliseconds"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the correct expression for the length of UDP datagram payload ?",
        "answers": [
            "UDP length = UDP length + UDP header’s length",
            "UDP length = UDP length – UDP header’s length",
            "UDP length = IP length + IP header’s length",
            "UDP length = IP length – IP header’s length -UDP header length"
        ],
        "correct": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will you get if you 'or' together the netmask of a network and one IP in that network?",
        "answers": ["Nothing significant", "The first IP address in the class of the given IP", "The last IP in the class of the given IP", "The class of the IP."],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Write the network mask (only as /x.y.z.t) of the minimum sized network that contain both 80.81.82.83 and 80.83.84.85.",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "255.252.0.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is true about ICMP packets ?",
        "answers": [
            "They do not provide hosts with information about network problems.",
            "They guarantee datagram delivery.",
            "They are encapsulated within IP datagrams.",
            "ICMP is encapsulated within UDP datagrams"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cannot be a broadcast address ?",
        "answers": ["192.168.1.255", "22.21.20.19", "10.20.30.255", "20.19.18.17", "21.20.19.18"],
        "correct": "de"
    },
    {
        "question": "All IP addresses from the class 10.0.0.0/16 are private",
        "answers": ["true", "false"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true about the IP address 10.16.3.65/23?",
        "answers": [
            ". The broadcast address of the subnet is 10.16.3.254",
            "The subnet address is 10.16.3.0/255.255.254.0",
            "The lowest host address in the subnet is 10.16.2.1",
            "The last valid host address in the subnet is 10.16.2.254"
        ],
        "correct": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have an interface on a router with the IP address of 192.168.192.10/29. Including the router interface, how many hosts can have IP addresses on the LAN attached to the router interface?",
        "answers": ["5", "6", "8", "7"],
        "correct": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the broadcast address for IP combination 132.45.99.0/19?",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "132.45.127.255"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the network address and mask of the smallest subnet that fits these two IP addresses: 180.181.182.183 and 180.186.12.180? (addr/x.y.z.t format)",
        "answers": [],
        "correct": "180.176.0.0/255.240.0.0"
    }
]
